给我乖乖待着
Stay down!
不准乱动
Don't move!
搞定
Yeah!
求救求救 这里是顽童二号
Mayday! Mayday! This is the Sawyer-Two.
我们遭遇海盗攻击
We're under attack by pirates.
请求即刻救援
Requesting an immediate aid.
大家总说每人各有特长
They say everybody's good at something.
而我 能与鱼类沟通
Me? I talk to fish.
我也因此结识好友暴风
That's how I met my friend, Storm.
我需要坐骑时它总会出现
He's always there when I need a lift.
有些人因此觉得我很搞笑 但我不在乎
Some people think that makes me a joke. But I don't care.
知道为什么吗? 因为我还有别的强项
You know why? 'Cause I'm also good at something else.
那就是擅长爆头
And that's breaking heads.
老爸单挑所有海盗
Pow! Papa took on all the pirates.
我说:"你们海盗以为..."
I was like, "Well, the pirates think that..."
你老爸打趴他们
Papa kicked their butts.
那些杂碎根本毫无胜算
Those chum lickers didn't stand a chance.
把他们打成满地找牙的猪头
Papa kicked their asses and took their names.
好耶 太棒了
Yeah! Come on!
小心
Watch out.
抱歉老爹 是我不对
Sorry, Pops. My bad.
对了 那是我儿子 小亚瑟
Oh, yeah, this is my son, Arthur Jr.
四年前 我的人生完全改变
See, four years ago, everything changed.
我遇见一位美女 坠入爱河
I met a woman, fell in love,
然后转眼间...
and the next thing I know,
我们已结婚生子
we're getting married and having a kid.
这个小家伙是我此生最棒的礼物
This little guy's the best thing that ever happened to me.
但这小子 他从不乖乖睡觉
But this kid, he doesn't sleep.
你尿布里面藏了什么?
What you got in there, huh?
好了...
Okay...
而且他总是命中目标
And he never misses.
搞什么...
What the...
所以我总是超早起床
And then, I'm up at the crack of dawn
因为除了结婚生子之外
because on top of getting married and having a kid...
我还终于找到一份工作
...I finally got a job.
没错
That's right.
在下正是亚特兰提斯之王
I'm the king of freaking Atlantis.
知道我是怎么坐上这位置的?
How did I score that, you asked?
我阻止我小弟欧姆攻击陆地世界
Well, I stopped my brother, Orm, from attacking the surface world.
在过程中 我剥夺了他的王位
And in doing so, I claimed the throne from him.
一开始我以为
At first I was all like...
好耶
Yeah!
领海的掌控权以前都是...
The territorial waters are long held...
然后我发现当国王其实没那么好玩
But then, as it turned out, being king wasn't all it was cracked up to be.
整天有开不完的政治会议
It's just meetings all day and politics.
快无聊死了 我都不知道对着盐海国王时
I'm so bored, I don't even know which end of the Brine King
眼睛该往哪看
I'm supposed to be looking at half the time.
好耶 真是太赞了
Yeah! That was awesome!
好像这还不够糟糕
And if that's not bad enough,
我更发现还有一个以前没人
turns out there's this whole Council of Houses thing
跟我提过的众议院
that nobody told me about.
他们有权否决所有我想做的事
Which basically gets to shoot down everything I want to do.
还好有我的小家伙作伴
The only thing that makes all the hard work
才不枉我那份苦差事和不眠夜
and sleepless nights worthwhile is hanging with my little man.
你没射中
Hey! You missed me!
当然这工作也有好玩的地方
But of course, there are fun parts of the job.
我得以用我的方式来维持海洋安全
I get to keep the sea safe the best way I know how.
特别是我还破获了几个非法铁笼格斗
Especially when I get to take down an illegal cage fight or two.
但不管我有多成功 还是会搞砸一些小事
But for everything I get right, something else gets screwed up.
喵的...
Ah, fu...
-好耶 -给你
- Oh, yeah. - Here you go.
他会需要手足来陪他玩
So... he's gonna need a little brother or sister to play with.
他有一只狗
He's got a dog.
我是认真的
Hey, I'm serious.
我亲眼看到你小时候有多寂寞
I saw how lonely it was for you growing up.
身为独生子
An only child.
我很遗憾没能给你更多手足
I always regretted I couldn't give you that.
别对自己太严苛
Yeah, well, don't be too hard on yourself.
结果我有个继弟 却是个混帐
Turns out I have a brother and he's a total dick bag.
别这样
Come on.
你跟欧姆的关系是特殊案例
Your relationship with Orm isn't how it usually is.
兄弟姐妹吵架很正常 但大家总归是家人
Sure, siblings bicker and fight... but at the end of the day, they're family.
必要时应该能指望他们帮忙
You should be able to count on them for help.
是喔 若要找帮手我还是宁愿选狗
Yeah, well, I'll still take the dog over him any day.
喂 你快看
Hey, look at that.
不是吧
Holy crap.
小宝贝 你是在跟鱼说话吗?
Hi, baby boy. Are you talking to the fishies?
天啊老爹 这太让我惊喜了
Oh, man. Pops, this is blowing my mind.
我这辈子都希望能跟人分享这天赋
My whole life I've wanted to share this gift with someone.
儿子 你和我 我们与众不同 我们很特别
Yeah, but you and me, son, we're different. We're special.
我们是陆地与海洋间的桥梁
We're connected to the land and the sea.
我等不及要介绍你认识 世上所有神奇生物
I can't wait to introduce you to all the majestic creatures on our planet.
让你知道这世界能有多棒
And show you how awesome this world can be.
对 你我一起
Yeah, you and me.
我交叉比对了沈博士的座标 结果一无所获
I cross-referenced the coordinates from Dr. Shin. Nothing.
还是没能在冰下找到亚特兰提斯遗迹
Still no sign of Atlantean remnants under the ice.
看来他又带我们白跑一趟了
Looks like he's led us on another wild goose chase.
只要我一天不修好动力装甲 海王就能多苟活一天
Every day I don't fix my power suit is another day Aquaman gets to live.
再查一次
Check again.
这次很接近了 我有预感
We're close this time. I can feel it.
探险日志第463日 史蒂芬沈博士录音
Expedition log day 463, Dr. Stephen Shin recording.
为了寻找亚特兰提斯 我走遍了全世界
My quest for Atlantis has brought me to the ends of the earth.
大卫凯恩逐渐失去耐心
David Kane is losing his patience.
若我不尽快找到他想要的 亚特兰提斯科技
If I don't turn up the Atlantean technology he's looking for soon,
他们大概会...
they're probably going to... um...
还是不提那个了 我相信一切都会顺利的
You know what, let's not even go there. I'm sure everything will be fine.
沈博士 快来看
Dr. Shin, take a look at this.
拜托告诉我你有线索了
Please tell me you found something.
地震仪上的读数超扯的
Seismic array is going crazy.
震央在哪?
Where's the epicenter?
就在我们脚下
We're standing on it.
快逃啊
Run!
发生什么事了 是地震吗?
What just happened? An earthquake?
不是 应该是一片冰盖脱落了
No. I think it was a piece of ice sheet breaking off.
快点 站起来
Come on. Get up.
-我的脚踝好像断了 -快点 我们走
- I think I broke my ankle! - Come on. Let's go!
快点起来 我们得走了
Come on, get up. Go, we gotta go! We gotta go!
快点 我们得离开 快点
Come on, we gotta move! Come on!
（发射讯号）
拜托 拜托 救我
Please, please. No, no!
救我 拜托 别放手
Help, please! Don't let go!
你发生什么事了?
What the hell happened to you?
那后面有恐怖的东西
There's something back there.
太神奇了
Astounding.
读数显示下面有东西
My readings show something's down here.
尺寸大到可能是亚特兰提斯船舰
And it's definitely big enough to be an Atlantean ship.
若真的是 就可能在上面 找到能修理你动力装甲的科技
If it is, we might be able to scavenge the tech you need to fix your suit.
这地方怎么可能真实存在?
How is this place even possible?
在地球持续升温前 这里应该被冰封了
This was all probably solid ice until we started heating the planet.
感谢温室效应 对吧?
Well, thank God for global warming, am I right?
那个 应该不算什么好事
Uh, yeah, that's not exactly a good thing.
足迹都往下走
The tracks lead down there.
穿上装备
Suit up.
等等 足迹都往下走
Wait. The tracks lead down there,
意思是怪兽也在下面
which means... the monster's down there.
好吧 我猜我们要下去
Okay. I guess we're going down there.
太不可思议了
I don't believe this.
这是某种建物
It's a structure of some kind.
冰里埋藏着更多东西
And there's more buried in the ice.
本来以为我们只会找到船舰
Here I thought we were just going to find a ship.
-所有人 散开搜寻 -收到
- Everyone, fan out and search. - Yes, sir.
我们侥幸撞见大发现了 博士
We've stumbled upon something big here, doc.
这肯定有几千年的历史
This has to be a few thousand years old.
太神奇了
Astounding.
这到底是什么地方?
What is this place?
终于 你找到这里了
At last, you are here.
将我从监禁中释放
Free me from my prison
我就会赐予你力量
and I will grant you the strength
好杀死谋害你父亲之人
to kill the man who murdered your father.
你不能这样丢下他
You can't leave him like this!
自己去跟大海求饶吧
You ask the sea for mercy.
快走 你得活下去 才能杀了那个混帐
Get out of here! You need to live so you can kill that son of a bitch!
你会夺回他剥夺你的一切
You will take from him what he stole from you.
让他的家园燃烧
His home will burn
让他的王国在我的军团前瓦解
and his kingdom will fall before my legions.
大卫 不要 大卫
David. No, David.
大卫
David! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
大卫 大卫 没事的
David. David, it's okay.
你没事
You're all right.
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is that thing?
（五个月后）
世界各地传来惊人影像
...Just unbelievable footage coming in from all around the world.
各位观众晚安
Good evening, folks.
过去五个月来 世界各地
In the past five months, we've seen an extraordinary rise in temperatures
都传来破纪录的升温
reported around the world.
也因此导致许多前所未见的极端气候
And that has resulted in some of the wildest weather we've ever seen.
是的 在德州达拉斯发生了雷雪
Yes, this is thundersnow in Dallas, Texas.
能见度趋近零 今晚预计的降雪量
Visibility is near zero... and there's more snow expected tonight
会超过达拉斯往常全年总和
than Dallas usually sees in an entire year.
这仅是全球气候异象的一小部分
It's only one part of a worldwide weather phenomenon
完全是前所未见
unlike anything we've ever seen before.
亚瑟
Arthur.
议院召开紧急会议
The Council's called for an emergency gathering.
又爆发另一起瘟疫
There's been another plague outbreak.
连科学家都无法解释
...scientists are at a loss to explain.
但真正的问题是
But the real question is,
这还会持续多长时间? 气温最后又会有多热?
how long will it continue? And how much hotter is it going to get?
（亚特兰提斯议院）
这次是在哪里爆发?
Where did it hit this time?
亚特兰提斯的第九区
The Ninth Tride of Atlantis,
现在人鱼王国也传出疫情
and there are now reports of outbreaks in the Fishermen Kingdom as well.
已经好几世纪没有这样的疫情
There haven't been outbreaks like this in centuries.
为何会现在出现?
Why now?
海洋酸化、溶氧量降低、毒性藻华
Increased ocean acidity, decreased oxygen levels, toxic algal blooms.
原因任君选择
Take your pick.
陆地居民过去一世纪以来 不断戕害我们环境
The surface has been poisoning our atmosphere for over a century.
若他们不清楚我们的存在
You can't expect them to care about what happens to us
又怎能奢望他们关心我们的处境
if they don't even know we exist.
若我们想开始交涉协调
If you want to be a part of the conversation,
就得先站出来发声
we have to take our seat at the table.
是时候让亚特兰提斯 在陆地世界前现身了
It's time for Atlantis to reveal itself to the surface.
陛下应该很清楚议院对此举的看法
Your majesty is well aware of the Council's position on this.
听着 我们可以与人类科学家沟通 结合双方科技
Listen, we can talk to their scientists and combine our technologies
来扭转他们所造成的损害
to reverse the damage that they've already done.
我知道这有违我们传统 但这世界正逐渐缩小
And I know this is against our traditions, but the world is shrinking,
传统作法已无法保护我们
and the old ways aren't gonna protect us anymore.
时代已经改变
Times have changed.
亚特兰提斯渴望改变
Atlantis wants this.
许多新世代已不愿再躲藏
There's a whole generation out there that don't want to hide anymore.
你难道忘了正是这种瘟疫
Have you already forgotten that this plague
害死了你最敬爱的导师
killed your own beloved mentor,
你现在竟然会想与他们和谈?
and you want to negotiate with them?
我们赋予你小弟战争权 与海洋领主的称号不是没有原因的
We gave your brother war powers and made him Ocean Master for a reason.
若我们想让陆地居民知道我们的存在
If we ever decide to make ourselves known to the surface-dwellers,
会是为了歼灭他们 而不是共存
it will be to eradicate them, not to co-exist.
厉害吧
Hey, not bad.
我以前哄你睡觉得花两倍时间
Used to take me twice as long to get you to go to sleep.
真不知你是怎么办到的 老爸
I don't know how you did it, Pops.
梅拉与我有整个王国帮助
Mera and I have the whole kingdom helping us,
但这小家伙还是快把我们整死了
but that little baby boy is still kicking our asses.
而你
And you...
独自照顾我 扶养我长大
taking care of me, raising me on your own...
你才是真正的超级英雄
You're the real superhero.
敬单亲父母
To single parents.
毕竟我的工作没有你的那么高压
Well, my job was a little less stressful than yours.
是喔 但我这工作干得糟透了
Yeah, well, I just plain suck at my job.
武尔科嘱咐我要促进海洋与陆地团结
Vulko told me to bring the land and the sea together.
问题是亚特兰提斯 有半数人仍想摧毁陆地
The problem is half of Atlantis still wants to destroy the surface.
他们拒绝沟通 我什么也推动不了
They won't listen. I can't bring shit together.
武尔科相信你 是吧
Vulko believed in you. Aye.
我知道
I know.
我想念他
I miss him.
喂
Hey.
你无法拯救每一个人 儿子
You can't save them all, son.
你想知道我是怎么独自养大你的?
You really want to know how I raised you here by myself?
我只是埋头苦干
I just kept going.
事情顺利时欢庆 失败时则记取教训
You celebrate the wins, you mourn the losses.
隔天醒来继续加油
And you wake up the next day and you do it again.
有时最勇敢的举动就是永不放弃
Sometimes not giving up is the most heroic thing you can do.
（大西洋某处）
人体构造先天就不该去适应这种深度
Humans were not made to live at these depths.
别担心这点
Yeah, don't worry about that.
你只需记得这艘船是谁打造的
You just remember who built this ship.
我比较担心是他们多久前建的
I'm more worried about how long ago they built it.
已迫近目标 开启隐形模式
We're coming up on it. Engage stealth mode.
喂 博士
Hey, doc.
快去你那座大炮旁备战
You stand ready with that big gun of yours.
探险日志第613天
Expedition log, day 613.
凯恩踏上我们此行最危险的任务
Kane is off on our most dangerous mission yet.
一个三人的八爪机舰渗透小组
A three man octobot infiltration team.
我们寻获的这些远古机械太神奇了
It's incredible that these ancient machines we found
这么多年后仍运作如常
still function after all these years.
我仅为符合需求稍加改造
All I did was retrofit them to our needs.
但它们需要一种特殊燃料维持运转
But they require a very specialized fuel to keep them running.
凯恩称之为奥利哈钢
Kane calls it orichalcum.
我不知道他这些知识都是从哪学来的
I don't know how he knows about this,
但从他寻获三叉戟那日就是如此
but it all started the day he found that trident.
突然间他精通以前无从了解的秘辛
Suddenly, he knows secrets that he couldn't possibly know,
包括取得奥利哈钢的唯一管道
including the only way to obtain this orichalcum
就是要从那些高度警戒的贮存场掠夺
is to steal it from highly-protected storage vaults.
我们即将打劫其中最危险的一处
And we're about to hit the most dangerous one of them all.
好 你有15分钟的作业时间
Okay, you have 15 minutes to get in and out.
没有犯错的空间
No margin for error.
从这走应能让你直接抵达
Yeah, this should take you through.
我们不希望发生正面冲突
We don't want any confrontation.
大卫 我们无法对抗他们整个大军
David, we can't fight their entire army.
保持警戒
Stay vigilant.
我们不清楚他们有何种的防御机制
We have no idea what kind of security measures they have down there.
（奥利哈钢贮存场）
开始提取
Commencing extraction.
小心点 这东西易燃易爆
Be careful. It's highly volatile.
开始装载驳船
Loading barge now.
刺魟 改变计划
Stingray, change of plans.
我需要即刻协助撤离
I need an extraction now!
全体进入备战状态
All hands to battle stations.
（亚特兰提斯王国）
太神奇了
Astounding.
不明入侵船舰请注意
Attention, unidentified vessel.
-这里不是过境区域 -博士
- You are out of the transit zone. - Doctor,
快点开启音波电池充电
power up the sonic battery.
非法越境将遭受
Illegal border crossing will be met with
-致命武力打击 -现在
- deadly force. - Now!
开始充电
Commencing charge.
边防检查管制 入侵者逼近
Border Control, intruder approaching.
武装高压水炮并锁定目标
Arm hydro cannon and lock target.
前边境大门高压水炮已锁定目标
Hydro cannon at front border gate locking in on target.
充电率已设定为最大功率
Chargers set to maximum power.
（防护罩启动）
入侵者现身
Intruder in sight.
消灭他们
Take them out!
你们在等什么? 开火啊
What are you waiting for? Fire!
长官 亚特兰提斯敌军正在逼近
Sir, Atlantean hostiles are approaching.
分头行动 自行前往撤离点
Split up. Make your way to the extraction point.
收到
Roger.
他们抢了贮存场 我们不能让他们跑了
They've raided the storage vault. We can't let them get away.
别担心 他们跑不了 我来追击
Don't worry, they won't. I'm on this one.
暂停开火 他们在穿越夜市
Hold your fire! They're cutting through the Night Market.
小心路人安全
Watch out for the civilians.
警告 警告 非法进入超管区
Warning. Warning. Illegal entrance into hypertube.
超越600节最高限速
Exceeding maximum speed of 600 knots.
即刻减速
Reduce speed immediately.
惨了
Oh, shit.
大卫 我们已抵达撤离点
David, we're here at the extraction point.
奥利哈钢已到手并安好
The orichalcum is onboard and secure.
快点 我们走了
Come on, let's go!
不 还不行
Not yet!
我要先杀几个人鱼再走
I'm gonna kill me a dead mermaid.
离我老婆远点
Get away from my wife!
你老婆?
Your wife?
你先是夺走小弟的王位
First you steal your brother's throne,
然后连他女人都抢了?
then you steal his woman?
海王 你真可耻
Aquaman, shame on you.
大卫 我们得闪了
Uh, David, we gotta go.
整个亚特兰提斯大军正往这赶来
The entire Atlantean army is headed this way.
若我们不现在离开 就死定了
If we don't leave now, we're dead.
左舷20度
Twenty degrees port!
发射音波炮
Fire the sonic cannon!
快啊 老沈
Come on, Shin!
凯鲨夫人在高级议院召开紧急会议
Lady Karshon has called an emergency session of the High Council
以讨论剥夺王座行政权力的动议
to discuss a motion that would strip the throne of its executive power.
王座本该是亚特兰提斯的根本
The throne is the heart of Atlantis.
然而王座现在却经常空虚
Too often now it stands empty,
只因国王有一半时间在陆地游荡
while our king spends half his time on land.
现在他在陆地的仇家更尾随他回家
And now his surface world enemies have followed him home.
若亚特兰提斯在世人面前现身
This tragedy is merely a taste of the havoc that will be wrought,
这次的悲剧只会是冰山一角
if Atlantis ever becomes known to the surface.
因为若他连自己家人都保护不了
Because if he cannot protect his own family,
又如何能保护我们?
how is he supposed to protect us?
他跟之前不同 也更为强大
He's different now. He's stronger than before.
连不穿动力装甲都能跟我对打
And he can fight me without the power suit.
他那些新武器又是从哪来的?
And where the hell did he get all the new toys from?
那些科技看起来很古老 但我们从未见过
The technology seems ancient, but we've never seen anything like it.
他使用的武器射出某种超音波能量
That weapon he used fires some kind of ultrasonic energy
能干扰神经系统
that disrupts the nervous system.
我们知道被盗走什么吗?
Do we know what was stolen?
他带着大量的奥利哈钢库存潜逃了
He escaped with a large stockpile of orichalcum.
我该知道那是什么吗?
Am I supposed to know what that is?
奥利哈钢是远古时代使用的能量源
Orichalcum is a power source that was used in ancient times.
会排放大量的温室气体
It emits tremendous amounts of greenhouse gases
对地球造成重大伤害
that are highly destructive to our planet.
事实上 在我们察觉这点前
In fact, we almost destroyed the oceans ourselves
我们自己也差点毁了海洋
before we realized what we were doing.
这物质无法被安全处置 所以我们将剩余的库存
It can't be disposed of safely, so the remaining stockpile
分别埋在地底深处的12个贮存场中
has been buried in 12 storage vaults deep underground.
我们该警告其他的贮存场
We should warn the other places that are storing the stuff.
他早就打劫过了 库存全没了
He's already been there. It's all gone.
我们认为他过去五个月 一直在暗中袭击
We think he's been launching secret raids for at least five months.
只是这次不小心被抓到
This is just the time he got caught.
这波全球气温飙高 在陆地酿灾
Well, this spike in global temperatures that's causing disasters on the surface
并让陆地居民生病的灾情 也是五个月前开始的
and making the sea dwellers sick happened five months ago.
他用偷来的奥利哈钢来加速地球暖化
He's using the stolen orichalcum to heat the planet.
他为何要如此?
Why would he do that?
我不知道 但我会查个清楚
I don't know, but I'm gonna find out.
若他在用奥利哈钢加温地球
If he is using the orichalcum to heat the planet,
我们的时间就不多了
we don't have much time.
他已将此效应推越临界点
He is pushing this past the tipping point.
我们必须阻止他 不然全球气候崩盘迫在眉睫
He must be stopped or a global climate meltdown is imminent.
我们需要找到他 但他目前消失无踪
We need to find him, but he's completely vanished off the radar.
我想我知道有谁能帮助我们
I think I know someone who might be able to help us.
但你们肯定不会喜欢
But you're not gonna like it.
你小弟?
Your brother?
相信我 他是我最不愿意求援的对象
Believe me, he's the last person I wanna go begging for help,
但他以前跟黑蝠鲼交易过
but he's dealt with Manta in the past,
所以唯有他可能知道如何快速找到他
and he's the only one who might know how to find him in time.
人鱼王国不会让你见欧姆的
The Fishermen will never allow you to speak to Orm.
他杀死他们的国王
He killed their king.
我也没想去请求他们许可
I wasn't exactly gonna ask for permission.
亚瑟 亚特兰提斯 无法要求同盟国交出欧姆
Arthur, Atlantis cannot extract Orm from an allied nation.
那等同于宣战
It would be an act of war.
不用亚特兰提斯出面
Atlantis isn't gonna do it.
我会自己去把他劫出来
I'm gonna break him out myself.
亚瑟 凯鲨正想找借口剥夺你的战争权
Arthur, Karshon is looking for a reason to seize war powers.
若她真那么做 你的王位就只剩头衔
You will be nothing more than a figurehead if she does that.
我的主场本来就在外界 在那里我能做出真实贡献
My place is out there where I belong, where I'm actually good at what I do.
我厌倦了束手束脚的日子
I'm tired of nothing ever getting done.
我非得这么做不可
I've got to do this.
若被人发现 若你被抓到...
If anyone finds out, if you're caught...
那会分裂所有王国
it will tear the kingdoms apart.
那就帮我别被抓到
Then help me not get caught.
泽贝尔情报处最近查出你小弟
Xebelian intelligence has recently learned that your brother
被关押在陆地上的一处地下秘密基地
is being held on the surface in a secret one-of-a-kind underground facility.
他们以为海洋居民没有勇气横渡沙漠
They're assuming no sea dweller would ever dare cross the desert.
（原沙漠王国监狱 今人鱼王国领地）
我替你准备了特殊服装
And here's a special outfit for you.
这算什么? 童装中号?
What is that, boy's extra medium?
这原本就是紧身衣
It's supposed to be tight.
色素细胞能改变颜色 维持隐身长达一分钟
The chromatophores change color and camouflage you for up to a minute,
让你能躲过大多数监测器
making you undetectable to most sensors.
攻他们一个措手不及
They'll never see you coming.
通讯部分要怎么处理?
What are we doing for comms?
开放式通讯风险太大
Open comms are too risky.
我会派一只头足类来充当你的传令兵
I'll be sending a cephalopod with you to act as a messenger.
那是一只章鱼
That's an octopus.
战术运筹与追击侦察专员
Tactical Operations and Pursuit Operative.
简称土拨
Topo, for short.
基因工程智力进化 用于渗透和间谍活动
Genetically engineered intelligence for infiltration and espionage.
它还会弹奏多种乐器
He also plays a variety of musical instruments.
等我们到了后记得保持低调 好吗?
Just try and lay low when we get in there, okay?
你或许是隐形的 但你的交接腕
You might be invisible, but your hectocotylus
开始闻起来像死鱼海底捞
is starting to smell like warm chum butter.
土拨 你这只笨鱿鱼
Topo, you dumb squid!
老天 拜托你
God, come on!
墨汁算是排泄物吗?
Is ink piss?
这座监狱由恐怖的沙漠王国残兵看守
The prison is guarded by fearsome Deserter remnants.
它们是撒哈拉沙漠化后 幸存下来的厌世苦行僧
Death-worshipping ascetics who survived when the Sahara went dry
以血液为生
by turning to blood for sustenance.
若它们捕获你 就会吸干你的血液
If they catch you, they'll bleed you dry.
你找到欧姆时 他会很虚弱
When you find Orm, he'll be weak.
它们会限制他的供水量
They're limiting his water supply...
维持他勉强存活
just enough to keep him alive.
等你见到欧姆时 告诉他我爱他
And if you do see Orm, you tell him that I love him.
告诉他我每天都想着他
You tell him that I think of him every day.
我会的
I will.
听着 我知道他是你们血亲
Look, I know he's family,
但别忘了他是什么人
but you can't forget who you're dealing with here.
一旦你把欧姆劫出来
Once you've broken Orm out,
就得时刻防备他从背后捅刀
you're not gonna be able to turn your back on him.
你需要他 但不能信任他
You need him, but you can never trust him.
你看起来真糟糕
You look rough.
见鬼了 你来这干嘛?
What the hell are you doing here?
我是来把你劫走的
I'm here to break you out.
你疯了吗?
Have you lost your mind?
是你害我被关进来的
You're the one who put me here.
干嘛一直翻旧帐 走吧 我们晚点再叙旧
Eh, why you bringing up old shit? We'll talk about it later.
你不能把我劫出去
You cannot break me out.
亚特兰提斯与人鱼王国间有协定
There's a treaty with the Fishermen Kingdom.
听着 我得阻止大卫凯恩毁灭世界
Look, I gotta stop David Kane from destroying the world.
只有你帮得了我 你自己评估一下
And you're the only one that can help me. So you do the math.
该死 来吧荒岛男 带上你的威尔森 该闪了
Oh, shit. Come on, Cast Away. Grab Wilson. Let's roll.
快点 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
这不代表我们扯平了
This changes nothing.
正合我意 小弟
Wouldn't have it any other way, little brother.
别叫我小弟
Do not call me "brother."
别这样
Come on.
快点 土拨 你这只笨鱿鱼 快醒来帮我们开门
Come on, Topo, you stupid squid! Wake up and open the door.
土拨?
Topo?
那只头足类?
The cephalopod?
相信我 那不是我的主意
Trust me, it wasn't my idea.
土拨
Topo!
好了 走吧
All right, come on.
等等
Wait.
你有...带水来吗?
Did you... bring water?
有啊
Yeah.
不对 不好意思
Uh, no, sorry.
我在路上喝光了
I drank it all on the way here.
-什么? -老弟 沙漠很热耶
- What? - Bro, it's hot up there.
你这只小虫
Ah, you monster!
喂 放轻松
Whoa! Easy.
-知道怎么骑这玩意吗? -你开什么玩笑
- You know how to ride one of these? - Are you kidding?
-我甚至不知道这是什么 -什么?
- I don't even know what the hell it is. - What?
好耶
Yeah!
好了 水岸就在那边
All right, the water's right there.
快去吧 纸片男
Let's go, skinny jeans.
对 就是这样
Yeah. All right.
干得好 小弟 来击掌
Good job, little brother. High-five.
才不要
No.
好吧 还是干得好
All right. Good job.
我在亚特兰提斯还有一堆 国王的公务要做 我们该走了
You know, I got a bunch of king shit to do back in Atlantis so we should go.
走了 土拨
Come on, Topo!
这比我想像中更糟糕
This is worse than I could have possibly imagined.
亚特兰提斯的安全和保障 是一种神圣的托付
The safety and security of Atlantis is a sacred trust.
过去一百世代 没有国王曾让国土遭受入侵
No king has allowed the great city wall to be breached in a hundred generations.
一百世代? 真的假的?
A hundred generations? Really?
那是多少年?
How many years is that?
我地质学不太好 算起来有一百万年吗?
I'm bad with geology. What is that, like, a million years?
还是你认为我是百万里挑一?
You're calling me one in a million?
这种时候你还有心情开玩笑?
How can you make jokes at a time like this?
国王乱开玩笑很有失尊严
It's undignified for a king to jest.
不好意思 尊贵的殿下 我只是爱用开玩笑
Oh, excuse me, Your Highness, if I use comedy
来掩饰自己的感情和纾解压力
to mask my feelings and deal with stress.
不这么做我就会变得像你一样 又紧绷又机车
Otherwise, I'd end up looking like you. A very tight butthole.
无敌龟毛
Super tight.
你知道 若担任领导的压力太大
You know, if the pressures of leadership are too stressful,
或许你应该退位 让更胜任的人成为国王
perhaps you should leave and let someone who knows what they're doing be king.
知道吗?
You know what?
等一切结束后 我等不及要送你回监狱了
I cannot wait to throw your ass back in prison when this is all over.
不用你送 等我们阻止了大卫凯恩
You won't have to. Once I stop David Kane,
我会自行向人鱼王国投案
I'll surrender myself to the Fishermen.
那是我对亚特兰提斯效忠的方式
That is my honor to Atlantis.
你真的很戏剧化
You're so dramatic.
随便你 只要帮我找到那混蛋就行
Whatever. Just help me find this asshole.
我的联系人会知道该从哪找起
Well, my contact will at least know where to look.
他到底发生什么事了?
What happened to him?
我认识的大卫凯恩只是行事不羁 却不是个疯子
David Kane that I knew was ruthless, but he wasn't insane.
现在这家伙却拿着枪 架上世界的脑袋并开枪
This guy just put a gun to the world's head and pulled the trigger.
甚至连条件都不先谈
Without even making any demands.
（远古奥利哈钢精炼厂）
恭喜你 沈博士
Congratulations, Dr. Shin.
你那音波炮的功效跟你说的一样强大
That cannon of yours worked exactly how you said it would.
东西是你找到的 我只是研究出该怎么用
Well, you found it. All I did was figure out how it worked.
我本来没想到会真的拿来轰人
I didn't think we'd ever actually have to use it on anyone.
这个嘛 怎么说呢?
Yeah, well, what can I say?
计划总是赶不上变化
Things don't always go as planned.
但那正是我所担心的
But that's what I'm afraid of.
大卫 这物质会重塑整个地球
David, this stuff could reshape the entire planet.
喂 博士
Hey, doc.
我们即将解锁人类史上最强大的力量
We are this close to unlocking the greatest power in human history.
别告诉我你真的想退出?
Are you really telling me you want to walk away now?
若我说是 你会放我走吗?
If I said yes, would you let me?
当然
Sure.
想知道你在丛林里能撑多久吗?
You want to see how long you last in that jungle?
欢迎去试
Be my guest.
算了 我还是留下来吧
Yeah, I'll stick around.
没错
Yeah.
欢迎来到最后边疆
Welcome to the last frontier.
他们从世界各地搜刮废弃船只 来建造此处
They scavenged ships from around the world to build this place.
人称沉没堡垒
The Sunken Citadel.
陆地与海洋界的败类 聚集在此处互相切磋
It is the one place in the world where the scum of the land and sea mingle.
人们更为了隐姓埋名而来到这里
It is where people come to disappear.
妈啊
Wow.
这个破山寨听起来真厉害
It's an impressive shithole.
为何我从未听说过这地方?
How have I never heard of this place before?
大家对此处避而不谈 这里是海盗的大本营
It is not meant to be common knowledge. It's a pirate haven.
海盗?
Pirates?
我不确定你是否知道这点
Listen, I don't know if you know this about me,
但海盗通常不太喜欢我
but I'm not too popular with pirates.
我非常清楚这点
Oh, I'm well aware.
放轻松 只有这样才能把我俩一起弄进去
Relax. It was the only way to get us both in.
你至少可以先警告我
You could've at least given me a heads up.
那样你会配合吗?
Would you have gone along with it?
-才不会 -那就闭嘴吧
- Hell, no. - Then put a hook in it.
在那里 那位就是王鱼
There. That's Kingfish.
当初就是它安排我和大卫凯恩接头的
He is the one who put me in contact with David Kane.
它专门替海盗、佣兵 和奴隶贩子担任白手套仲介
He brokers deals with pirates, mercenaries, slavers, you name it.
好酷
Cool.
我要去挑个事
I'm gonna go pick a fight.
交给我处理吧
Just let me handle this.
它是我们找到黑蝠鲼的最好机会
He's our best shot at finding Manta,
你若跑去它面前大秀肌肉
and he's not going to tell us anything if you go in there
它是什么都不会说的
flexing your muscles at him.
你很幸运我俩没有一起长大 小弟
You're so lucky we didn't grow up together, little brother.
别叫我小弟
Do not call me "brother."
唉唷唷
Well...
真是个大惊喜
This is a bit of a surprise, isn't it?
我没想到你已经被监狱释放了
I didn't realize you'd been released from prison.
我是最近才出狱的
It is a recent development.
反正我们都是亡命之徒 对吧?
Outlaws, aren't we all?
我们需要找到大卫凯恩
We need to find David Kane.
关于那点 恐怕我有坏消息
Bad news, I'm afraid.
大卫凯恩现在不接生意了
David Kane is no longer on the market.
多少钱都不接
Not for sale at any price.
他现在自己当老板 单打独斗
He's solely running as an independent operator.
他的藏身处在哪?
Where is he holed up now?
作为交换 我可以让
In exchange, I offer a favor...
亚特兰提斯之王欠你一次情
from the King of Atlantis.
你难不成真想让我跟那种
You seriously expect me to play footsie with someone
满手血腥的家伙打交道?
with that kind of blood on their hands?
可我没有手
I don't have hands!
也没有脚
Or feet!
听着 若是你提供的情报核实无误
Listen, if the information checks out good,
我保证我不会立刻回来拆了这地方
I promise you that I won't immediately come back here and tear this place apart.
那真是太可惜了
That's too bad.
道上规矩是亚特兰提斯之王 向来对沉没堡垒睁一只眼闭一只眼
Traditionally, the kings of Atlantis have turned a blind eye to the Sunken Citadel.
现在看来我们得手动替你闭眼了
Now, we have to blind it for you.
算了 你来大秀肌肉吧
Fine. Flex your muscles.
快打爆他的鸟头
Smash his stupid head in!
吃我一拳
Boom!
抓到你了 死胖子
Gotcha, fatback!
好啦好啦 万事好商量 我们聊聊
Okay! Okay! We can work this out. We can.
那你说啊
Talk.
我不知道他在哪 但最近有不少谣传
I don't know where he is, but there have been rumors.
南太平洋一个叫魔鬼深渊的休眠火山
A dormant volcano in the South Pacific, called "Devil's Deep."
再说快点
Talk faster.
那里曾经荒芜多年
It's been barren for years.
但旅人说最近当地出现丛林
But travelers say there's a jungle there now.
船只一旦靠近当地导航系统就会错乱
Navigation gets scrambled as soon as you start to get close.
若是太靠近 就会有去无回
And if you get too close, you don't come back!
若要我猜 而我真的是乱猜的
If I was a betting man, and believe me, I am,
我会说大卫凯恩藏在那里
I'd say that's where Kane is hiding out.
消息打听到了 我们走
We got all we needed. Let's go!
崛起 来吧 从火中崛起
♪ Rise up, come Rise up through the fire ♪
很快你就会比他更为强大
Soon you'll be more powerful than he is.
但你还没准备好 而且你太快让他入局了
But you're not ready yet, and you involved him far too soon.
我能感觉到他们的追兵
I sense them closing in on us.
我看起来很担心吗?
Do I seem concerned?
其实这样反而更方便
If anything, it's even easier now.
比我们原本自己计划得更...
We couldn't have planned it any better than...
嗨 我只是想告诉你奥利哈钢熔炉
Hey. I... I just wanted to tell you that the orichalcum furnace
现在正在以最大值输出
is now running at peak output.
（南太平洋某处）
（魔鬼深渊）
我赢了
I win.
土拨 回亚特兰提斯通报我们的方位
Topo, go back to Atlantis and give them our coordinates.
你知道现在有什么会很棒吗?
You know what'd be amazing right now?
援兵?
Reinforcements?
超大又多汁的起司汉堡 再加上一大杯黑啤酒
Great, big, greasy cheeseburger and a pint of Guinness.
你得承认 陆地的食物真的好吃很多
You gotta admit, the food is so much better up here.
这种说法有点离谱
I find that hard to believe.
等等
Hold up.
你是说你从没为了起司汉堡上岸过?
You telling me you never went topside to have a cheeseburger?
-什么? -或是为了腊肠披萨?
- What? - Or a slice of 'za? Pepperoni?
或是为了超厚半生牛排 配上薯条和奶昔 再沾上...
Or a thick, juicy, medium raw steak with fries and a shake, and you dip it...
就连陆地居民食物的名称 听起来都很恶心
Even the words that surface-dwellers give their food sound disgusting.
因为偏见 你失去享受半个世界的乐趣
You've let your prejudices stop you from enjoying half the world.
你该好好反思 那是你的损失 兄弟
You should think about that. It's your loss, dude.
好耶
Aw, yeah!
我打赌你从没吃过这个
Bet you never had one of these.
-那是什么? -蟑螂
- What is it? - It's a cockroach.
你们会吃这个?
You eat it?
对啊 这等同陆地的鲜虾
Oh, yeah. Shrimp of the land.
对吧 很好吃 来 这个给你喝
Eh? That's good. Here, drink this.
好 你先请
Okay, you first.
你有看到这个吗?
Are you seeing this?
这不正常吗?
That's not normal?
肯定不正常
Definitely not normal. Ugh.
我们走吧 现在你知道奥利哈钢有多危险了
Let's get out of here. You see how dangerous the orichalcum can be?
我打赌那在短时间内 让岛上动植物都变异了
I bet it mutated the flora and fauna in a short amount of time,
变得超...巨大
turning them... monstrous.
糟糕
Oh, shit...
快逃啊
Run!
快点
Come on.
再跑快点
Faster!
你在耍什么宝?
What the hell are you doing?
我不知道 我不太习惯跑步
I don't know. I'm not used to running.
跟着我做
Just do what I do.
用手臂和腿 手刀摆动起来
Use your arms, use your legs. Lift them up.
像这样吗?
Like this?
-你不是吧 -好耶
- Holy shit. - Yeah!
-等等我 -好耶
- Wait up. - Yeah!
我们得跳下去 这高度摔不死
We have to jump. We'll survive the fall.
你疯了吗? 那会很痛
Are you crazy? It's gonna hurt.
不然你想怎样? 留在这里跟跳跳鬼打一架?
What do you wanna do, stay here and fight the hopping demons?
那是什么? 上面写什么?
What is that? What does that say?
那是古老的亚特兰提斯语
The writing is ancient Atlantean.
"真正的王者搭建桥梁"
"A true king builds bridges."
你想干嘛?
What are you doing?
你还有比这更瞎的主意吗?
Got any more krill-brained ideas?
你看 真正的王者搭建桥梁
See? A true king builds bridges.
那只是一种隐喻
That's a metaphor!
喔对 我忘记告诉你了
Hey! I forgot to tell you.
老妈说她很爱你
Mom says she loves you.
也总是想着你
She thinks about you all the time.
你干嘛挑现在告诉我?
Why the hell are you telling me this now?
我也不知道 懒得等待适当时机了
I don't know. I'm just tired of waiting for the right moment.
快点
Come on.
看来我的隐喻刚救了你一命
Looks like my metaphor just saved your ass.
大卫 我刚才做了更多测试 但这些数据很让人忧心
Uh, David? I just ran more tests, and this data is really disturbing.
我们得停止燃烧奥利哈钢
We have to stop burning the... orichalcum.
大卫?
David?
好吧 博士 既然你这么想知道我的大计
Okay, doc, you want to know my plan so bad.
那就告诉你吧
Here it is.
我要干掉海王 毁掉他所珍视的一切
I'm gonna kill Aquaman and destroy everything he holds dear.
我要杀光他的家人 将他的王国焚烧殆尽
I'm gonna murder his family and burn his kingdom to ash.
我会为我父亲报仇
I will avenge my father.
就算得跟魔鬼交易也没问题
Even if I have to make a deal with the devil to do it.
大卫 你不能信任那支三叉戟
David, you can't trust the trident.
我从不轻易拔出这把匕首 除非确定能见血
I never draw this blade unless it's gonna taste blood.
你最好祈祷我不会再对你拔刀
Pray I never show it to you again.
我们肯定接近放射源了
We must be getting close to the radiation source.
我们该先等亚特兰提斯 接到通报再行动
We should wait for Atlantis to receive your message.
目前可以先行侦察
We can conduct reconnaissance in the meantime.
好喔 洛基 没人在问你的意见
Yeah. Look, Loki, I'm not asking for your advice on this.
你已经完成你的阶段任务
You've already lived up to your end of the deal.
欢迎你随时返回阿兹卡班
So you can go on back to Azkaban for all I care.
那你有何计划?
So, what's your plan?
我没计划
I don't have one, yet.
但他攻击我妻子 所以我非搞死他不可
But he came after my wife, which means I'm gonna pull his tongue out of his butt.
亚瑟 你是国王 不可意气用事
Arthur, you are the king. You cannot let this get personal.
当初拿整个王国来赌气的人
This coming from the guy who turned the entire nation of Atlantis
也好意思这么说?
into his own private ego trip?
我赌气?
My ego?
是你自己先来踢馆挑战我的王位
You're the one who swam through the front gate and challenged my claim for the throne.
那只是因为你想毁灭陆地世界
Only because you're trying to destroy the surface world.
若你没有那么恶劣 现在还会是国王
If you weren't such an asshole, you'd still be king.
太扯了
Unbelievable.
等等 等等
Wait, wait! Wait!
你抢了我的王位却根本不想要?
You took my throne and you don't even want it?
你是在搞笑吧? 我恨死这工作了
Are you kidding me? I hate this job.
我这样做纯粹是为了 防止亚特兰提斯毁灭陆地世界
Only reason I'm doing it is to keep Atlantis from destroying the surface.
而且我很可能正越搞越糟
And I might even be screwing that up.
你真的无心王位?
You really had no ambition for it?
完全无意
Absolutely not.
从我父亲发现你存在的那天起
From the day my father found out you existed,
他就训练我做好准备
he prepared me for the moment that you would come
以防你有朝一日来篡位
and challenge me for the throne.
那也太可悲了
Wow, that's really sad.
特别是我那么容易就打趴你
Especially when you think how easily I kicked your ass
根本不需准备工作
with basically no prep time whatsoever.
打脸了
Roasted.
事情经过不是那样的
That is not how it happened.
-事情的经过正是如此 -是梅拉救了你
- That's exactly how it happened. - Mera saved you.
她才没有 是我自己打趴你
No, she didn't. I kicked your ass.
才怪 她操纵了水龙卷 我被卷入其中
Nope. She made the little water tornado. I fell in it.
闭嘴 我们应该到了
Okay, shut up. I think we're here.
来吧 我们上吧
Come on, let's do this.
等一切完事后 我们该去吃汉堡喝啤酒
Once this is over with, we should go get some burgers and beers.
-别得寸进尺 -塔可和龙舌兰酒
- Don't push it. - Tacos and tequila.
根本没听过那些东西
I don't even know those words.
喂
Hey!
等等 小弟
Whoa, brother.
那是奥利哈钢熔炉
It's an orichalcum furnace.
所有被偷走的奥利哈钢
All that stolen orichalcum.
就这样烧个不停
They're just burning it up.
他是故意要让大气升温
He's heating the atmosphere on purpose.
这真是大灾难
This is catastrophic.
这地方肯定有隔热罩
This whole place must be heat-shielded
好躲过地表热能卫星的侦测
to protect it from the surface's thermal satellites.
问题是 要怎么阻止?
Question is, how do we stop 'em?
要摧毁这些反应炉 我们必须夷平整座岛屿
To take out this reactor, we would have to crater the entire island.
离控制台远点
Get away from there! Now!
这把雷射枪可能很古老 却是专为杀死亚特兰提斯人而制成
This blaster may be ancient, but it was built for killing Atlanteans.
好 很抱歉 我不是那个意思
Okay, I am so sorry. I did not mean that.
我只是怕你们会在我投降前先打死我
I just didn't want you to break me in half before I could surrender.
求你们带我走
Please take me with you.
敲昏他 然后帮我把这些人藏起来
Knock him out and then help me hide these bodies.
不 等等 拜托
No, no. Wait, please.
这完全不是我的本意
I didn't want any of this.
我原本只是想亲眼目睹亚特兰提斯
All I wanted was to see Atlantis with my own eyes.
我以为可以跟世界分享这奇迹
I thought I could share its wonders with the world.
我是科学家 只想被认真对待
I'm a scientist, and I just wanted to be taken seriously.
大卫凯恩说他能帮我 但现在他不放我离开
David Kane said he could help me, but now he won't let me leave.
你指望我们相信你跟这一切无关?
You expect us to believe you have nothing to do with this?
我知道
I know.
我做了些很不光彩的事
I've done things I'm not proud of.
但若我不照办他就会杀了我
But he would've killed me if I hadn't.
敲昏他
Knock him out.
不要
No.
-那我来敲昏他 -不行
- Then I'll knock him out. - No!
-什么? -不行
- What? - No.
好啦
Fine!
你可以跟我们一起走
You can come with us.
谢谢你们
Oh... thank you.
但你最好从实招来 否则就会被我毒打
But you better start talking. Or I'm gonna give you one sasa!
好啦 好啦
Okay, okay.
是那支黑色三叉戟 它连结着某种上古邪灵
It's the black trident. It's a direct link to some ancient evil.
它赋予凯恩强大力量 作为回馈...
It gives Kane great powers and in return...
我讨厌被炸飞
I hate when that happens.
阻止他们
Stop them!
不不 别用奥利哈钢
No, no, no, no, no! Not the orichalcum!
你想炸飞我们吗?
You wanna blow us up?
-这东西会爆炸? -对
- This stuff blows up? - Yes!
不好意思
My bad!
那就别用它来打斗
Then stop using it!
闭嘴乖乖等我来救你
Just shut up and let me save your ass.
又一次
Again.
他要不穿动力装甲跟我们打?
He's going to fight us without the power suit?
我跟你说过他变强大了
I told you he's stronger now.
但他还是一个陆地居民
He's still just a surface-dweller.
小弟
Bro!
我从未想过会看到你俩并肩作战
I never expected to see you two fighting side by side.
我们是特地为你合体的
We're making a special exception just for you.
谁都不准揍我弟 除了我以外
No one hits my brother but me.
我原本打算最后再去杀你 但多谢你主动来访
I was gonna kill you last, but thanks for dropping by.
你让我省了好多麻烦
You're making this easy.
对
Yeah!
放马过来
Come at me,
杀手级国王组
the killer of kings.
夷平这座岛
Take that island down!
自由开火
Fire at will!
我们得尽快离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
故障 故障 警告 警告
Malfunction. Malfunction. Warning. Warning.
老沈 快点
Shin, let's go!
你还在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
快发射音波炮
Fire the goddamn cannon!
抱歉害你们卷入这一切
I'm sorry to drag you all into this.
但我们不能让人鱼王国知道 亚特兰提斯有介入
But the Fishermen can't think that Atlantis was involved.
泽贝尔的军队归我管 不归亚特兰提斯管
Atlantis does not command the armies of Xebel. I do.
我们盐海王国仍然记得你的恩情
And the Brine Kingdom has not forgotten its debt to you.
有事总是可以找我们相助
You may count on us always.
当我手握黑色三叉戟时
Something happened to me.
有奇怪的事发生在我身上
When I touched that black trident.
他为何在这里?
Why is he even here?
他该在返回监狱的路上
He should be on his way back to prison.
我们该听听他要说什么
We should hear what he has to say.
这种错我犯过一次
I made that mistake once.
所以我知道不该相信他
That's why I know he can't be trusted.
他还砍断我的螯足
And he cut off my claw.
花了一整年才长回来
This thing took a whole year to grow back.
听着 他跟我们一样想阻止黑蝠鲼
Look, he wants to stop Manta same as we do.
说句公道话
And just for the record,
多亏了他我们才能追查到这里
the only reason we made it this far is because of him.
我看到了失落王国
I saw the Lost Kingdom.
妈 我对这些事了解不够深
Mom, I don't know enough about this.
这有可能吗?
Is that even possible?
大家只确切知道 曾有第七个王国的存在
All anyone knows for sure is there once was a seventh kingdom
然后在大沉没前的某天
and then one day, just before the fall,
该国历史被从所有史书中抹去
every record of it was stricken from the chronicles.
你怎么知道你看到的就是失落王国?
How do you know what you saw was the Lost Kingdom?
大家甚至不知道它的国名
No one even knows what it was called anymore.
它叫涅库斯
It's called Necrus.
我不仅仅有看到
And I didn't just see it.
我还心知肚明
I knew it.
那感觉就像是回忆起往日
It's almost like I was... remembering it.
陌生的记忆突然涌入脑海
Flashes of someone else's memories.
在亚特兰王在位期间 亚特兰提斯由七个联合王国组成
During King Atlan's time, there were seven united kingdoms of Atlantis.
而黑城就像是万恶的根源
And the Black City was a curse upon them all.
借由滥采奥利哈钢
By exploiting orichalcum,
涅库斯很快就成为超级强权
Necrus rapidly became a superpower unlike any other.
但这带来惨痛的代价
But it came at a terrible price.
污染陆地与海洋
Poisoning the land, the sea,
就连掌管涅库斯的暴君心智都被戕害
even the mind of the tyrant who ruled Necrus.
也就是亚特兰的亲弟弟寇达斯
Atlan's own brother, Kordax.
亚特兰央求他在造成 世界不可逆的损害前停止
Atlan pleaded with him to stop using it before the world was irrevocably damaged.
然而寇达斯却憎恨亚特兰
However, Kordax resented Atlan,
认为自己大哥只想窃取他的力量
thinking his own brother was trying to steal his power.
所以他求助黑魔法 并打造出邪恶法器
So, he resorted to dark magic and crafted an instrument of evil.
就是那黑色三叉戟
That black trident.
他将自己和子民幻化成怪兽
He transformed his people and himself into monsters...
好对抗亚特兰提斯
...to fight Atlantis.
两兄弟因此兵戎相见
So, the two brothers went to war.
但亚特兰击败了寇达斯 并用自己的鲜血施下魔咒
But Atlan defeated Kordax and imprisoned him and all of Necrus
好将他与涅库斯人民全数囚禁
with a spell cast with his own blood...
以确保寇达斯的黑魔法永远消失
...to ensure that Kordax's dark power would never be found.
涅库斯也因此被从史书中抹去
And that is why Necrus is stricken from the chronicles.
邪恶力量原本该永世被冰封
This evil was supposed to remain frozen for eternity.
但却被大卫凯恩寻获
But David Kane has found it.
那力量也逐渐掌控他
And it's slowly possessing him.
但即便冰帽融化 寇达斯仍无法重见天日
But even with the ice cap melting, Kordax still can't be freed.
亚特兰用鲜血魔咒 将寇达斯封锁在笼牢中
Atlan used blood magic to seal Kordax in his prison.
只有亚特兰才能释放他
Only Atlan himself could release him.
黑蝠鲼不需要亚特兰本人 只需要他的血
Manta doesn't need Atlan himself. Manta needs Atlan's blood.
血咒跟一般魔法不同 更像是DNA辨识
Blood magic isn't really magic, it's DNA.
想开启寇达斯的笼牢 就需要以皇室血亲鲜血为钥
The key to Kordax's prison is the royal bloodline itself.
意思是他需要你、我 或是亚瑟的血
That means he needs blood from either you, me or Arthur.
我们是王室最后血脉
We're the end of the bloodline.
不 我们不是
No, we're not.
原本世界各地就频传野火灾情
...Wildfires would have made headlines across the world,
现在更是几乎每周出现
but now, they're almost a weekly occurrence.
此刻全球正见证前所未有的气候异象
We're witnessing unprecedented weather events across the globe,
气象学家也不知该如何解释 全球气候的快速变迁
and meteorologists are at a loss to explain this rapid change in climate.
从炽热的热浪和干旱
From sweltering heatwaves and droughts,
不断打破高温记录 到暴雨和洪水
which are shattering temperature records, to torrential rains and floodings...
-到底怎么回事? -飓风席卷东岸
- What is going on? - ...hurricane bearing down on the East Coast,
让百万家庭面对断电...
leaving one million homes without power...
现在再加上我们一家
Make that a million and one.
我先去拿手电筒 小宝
I gotta get the flashlight, bubba.
我先留你活口 好让他能亲眼看你送命
I'm gonna leave you alive, so he can watch you die.
老爹
Dad!
-汤姆 -老爹
- Tom! - Dad!
汤姆
Tom!
不 老爹
No! Dad!
小亚瑟在哪?
Where's Junior?
汤姆 不
Tom! No!
抱歉 儿子
I'm sorry, son.
小亚瑟在哪?
Where's Junior?
黑蝠鲼...带走了小亚瑟
Manta... took Junior.
-不 -不
- No! - No!
不
No!
（发射座标）
（发射完毕）
医务兵已将他的情况稳定下来
The medics have stabilized his condition.
他不会有事
He will be okay.
我们刚收到讯号
We just picked up a signal.
很微弱 是从古老亚特兰提斯 声纳频率上传来的
It's faint, but it's broadcasting on an old Atlantean sonar frequency.
并往南极洲移动
Headed to Antarctica.
-去把小宝带回来 -我会的
- Bring our little one back. - I will.
我曾梦想过此刻
I've dreamed of this.
有朝一日你们俩能兄弟相挺
The two of you standing together as brothers.
答应我你们会保护彼此
Promise me you will protect each other.
答应我 欧姆
Promise me, Orm.
去吧
Go.
好炫的出行工具 涅罗斯
Great waves, Nereus.
你的战舰很强大 但速度竟慢过海牛
Your warship is powerful, but it's slower than a sea cow.
依我看还不如甩掉这破烂 轻骑出行
I say we ditch all this dead weight and travel light. Hmm?
那敌方发射音波炮时要怎么办?
And what are you gonna do when he turns on that sonic cannon?
我们唯一的胜算 就是用全方位压倒性的火力回击
Our only chance is to hit him with total overwhelming force from every direction.
-不能让小亚瑟置身火线中 -我们还有什么选择?
- Not with Junior in the crossfire. - What choice do we have?
我们无法抵抗那种炮火
We have no defense against that cannon.
等等
Well, wait a minute.
这种武器会发射音波 并干扰神经系统 对吧?
So this cannon sends out soundwaves that messes with our nervous system, right?
没错 是超音波回波
That's right. Ultrasonic echoes.
若我们发射同样频率的
Well, what if we disrupt those echoes
另一种音波来干扰回波
with another soundwave on the same frequency,
而且还更大声呢?
but just much, much louder?
你想用魔法打败魔法?
You wanna disrupt their disruption?
那会是容易的部分
Well, that's gonna be the easy part.
拿上你们的武器
Take your weapons.
准备好座骑
And ready your steeds.
他是真的不喜欢你 对吧?
Really doesn't like you, does he?
我们原本进展不错 博士
We made a lot of progress, doc.
虽然他们在我们大功告成前毁了熔炉
They destroyed the furnace before we could finish the job,
但我们很接近了
but we were damn close.
只要再朝正确位置 射颗飞弹就能搞定一切
One well-placed missile should do the trick.
我的老天 我们做了什么?
My God, what did we do?
反正这世界原本已开了头
Nothing the world wasn't already doing.
我们不过是让进程加快了几年
All we did was fast forward things a few years.
冰帽还没完全融化 但我们扫描发现了一个弱点
The ice hasn't fully melted yet, but our scanning reveals a weak spot.
这里
Here.
从这里能让你直达寇达斯
This will lead you straight to Kordax.
开启音波炮
Power up the sonic cannon.
带上那小鬼 着装
Bag the child and suit up.
队长 前方有多位敌军来袭
Captain, we have multiple incoming hostiles.
（飞弹武装完成）
你们来得太迟了
You're too late.
等...
No.
开始充电
Commence charge.
你是开玩笑的吧
You've got to be kidding me.
太神奇了
Astounding.
（失落王国涅库斯）
这里太大了 可能藏在任何地方
This place is immense. It could be anywhere.
涅库斯的王座位于城市的中心
The throne of Necrus is in the heart of the city.
-我感测到水中有东西 -所有人 点亮照明
- I sense something in the water. - Everyone, light it up.
你不是说寇达斯把他的人民 都变成怪兽军团了吗?
Didn't you say that Kordax turned his people into an army of monsters?
对 没错
Yes. I did.
眼睛睁大了
Keep your eyes open.
那很简单 反正我也闭不了眼
Well, that'll be easy. Mine don't close.
大家保持备战 前方有东西逼近
Everyone stand ready. Something's coming.
自由开火
Fire at will!
我们得找方法离开此处
We need to find a way out of here.
从这里应该能一路穿过去
I think this goes all the way through.
我的军队能对付这些虾兵蟹将
My men and I can deal with these worms.
你快去吧 把王子救回来
Go now and save the prince.
谢谢你 殿下
Thank you, Your Highness.
来啊 你们这些软脚虾
Come on, you spineless worms!
放马过来
Bring it on!
帮帮我
Help me!
把孩子给我
Give me the child.
你挑错日子良心发现了 博士
You picked the wrong day to grow a spine, doc.
快赶到吊闸后方
Get behind the portcullis!
我们需要关闭闸门
We need to close the gate!
离我儿子远点
Get away from my son!
反正用你的血也行
Your blood will do just fine.
你想要血? 就自己来取
You want blood? Come get it!
海王
Aquaman!
你身穿我哥的盔甲 手拿他的三叉戟
You wear my brother's armor, and wield his trident,
但你连他的一半都比不上
but you're only half the man he was.
真可悲
How pathetic.
梅拉
Mera!
你先走
Go!
梅拉
Mera...
快逃
Run!
将我从监禁中释放
Free me from my prison,
我的所有力量就会为你所用
and all my power will be yours to wield as you desire.
杀了他 你就能再度成为海洋领主
Kill him, and you will be Ocean Master again!
不错 现在这样终于好一点了
Well, now this is certainly an improvement.
强大的亚特兰提斯身躯
Powerful, Atlantean body.
而且这个人比之前那个更恨你
And this one hates you more than the other one did.
你说谎 别这样 小弟 我知道你听得见我
It's not true. Come on, little brother. I know you're in there.
你看不出来吗? 你赢不了的
Don't you see? You can't win.
你不是杀死你弟 就是等着自己受死
Either you kill your brother or you die.
凭藉亚特兰的血脉 魔咒终被破解
By an Atlan's blood, this magic is broken.
我的永夜已结束
My eternal night is ending.
我受够跟你的傀儡对打了 寇达斯
I'm done fighting your puppets, Kordax.
我要跟你对干
I'm coming for you.
-给我 -不要
- Give it to me! - No!
-我能了结这一切 -别让他夺走一切
- I can end this. - Don't let him take it!
难道他抢走的还不够多吗?
Hasn't he taken enough already?
放弃王位
Yield the throne.
是时候让我重新承启天命了
It's time for me to reclaim my destiny.
认为他能改变的想法实在太傻了
It would be foolish to think he could ever change.
我知道你会做到
I knew you would do this.
你才是独一无二的真正王者
You are the one true king.
亚特兰提斯值得拥有真正的王者
Atlantis deserves its one true king.
我才是独一无二的真正王者
I am the one true king!
你知道 我曾经有一度非常想见你
You know, there was a time when I wanted to meet you more than anything.
想让你知道你并不孤单 我俩能互相扶持
Let you know that you weren't alone, that we were in it together.
答应我 你俩会保护彼此
Promise me you'll protect each other.
来吧 小弟 让我们一起了结这个混蛋
Come on, little brother, let's end this bastard.
我俩第一次见面时 我说的都是真心话
I meant what I said when I first met you.
无论如何 你都不孤单
No matter what, you are not alone.
我俩可以一起承担
We're in this together.
你是我的兄弟
You are my brother.
欧姆
Orm.
放手吧
Let go.
欧姆 放手吧
Orm, let it go.
我终于重生了
I live again!
为了此刻 我在黑暗中苦等数世纪
I have waited countless centuries in the dark for this moment.
吃屎了
Shit.
亚瑟
Arthur!
绝不
Never.
亚瑟 我们得走了 魔咒已经崩解
Arthur, we've gotta go. The magic is broken.
我们快闪吧
Let's get outta here!
快点
Hurry!
没错
That's right!
来吧 宝贝 好耶
Come on, baby! Yeah!
好耶
Yeah!
吾爱
My love.
嗨 儿子
Hi, baby boy.
老沈
Shin.
谢谢你
Thank you.
太神奇了
Astounding.
看来大家都全身而退 很好 很好
All here looking intact. That's good. That's good.
但我没有 我的螯足被砍断了
Well, I'm not. My claw got cut off.
还是第二次
Again!
你是最强悍的甲壳纲动物 殿下
You're one tough crustacean, Your Highness.
依我来看 你的前罪已清
As far as I'm concerned, your debt is paid.
但不是所有人都会同意这点
Not everybody's gonna see it that way though.
真可惜你在战斗中不幸丧生了
It's too bad you went and had yourself killed back there.
对
Yes.
这么多浮冰
All this ice.
要找到尸体可不容易
It'd be impossible to find the body.
先低调一阵子
Just lay low for a while.
但别跑太远
But don't go too far.
我可能会需要你的辅佐
I may need to call you up for some advice.
像是如何管理王国那类的事
You know, with the whole running the kingdom thing.
谢谢你
Thank you...
大哥
brother.
你比你自己想像中做得好多了
You're not as bad at this as you think.
亚特兰提斯的人民很幸运能够拥有你
The people of Atlantis are lucky to have you.
你弥补了我所有的不足
You are everything I was not.
就算前景再困难 你仍能坚持正道
You do the right thing when doing the wrong thing is much easier.
你也愿意向往日宿敌开口求助
And you're willing to ask for help even from your worst enemy.
虽然有时你感觉不知道自己在做什么
I know it may not feel like you know what you're doing sometimes, but...
但请继续信任自己的直觉
keep trusting your instincts.
若你起身领导 亚特兰提斯必将跟随
If you lead, Atlantis will follow.
毕竟真正的王者会搭建桥梁
After all, a true king builds bridges, right?
我以为那只是个隐喻
I thought that was just a metaphor.
但你的隐喻刚刚拯救了全世界
Well, your metaphor might have just saved the world's ass.
刚刚传来即时新闻
We've got breaking news.
今日我们见证了历史
We are witnessing history.
其所带来的后果是...
A moment the ramifications of which simply...
无论如何强调都不为过
cannot be overstated.
海底王国
A first contact...
亚特兰提斯首度主动现身
...with the undersea nation of Atlantis.
一个隐身数千年的文明即将解密
An entire civilization hidden for thousands of years about to be revealed.
可以说世界从此将大为不同
I think it's safe to say the world will never be the same.
亚特兰提斯之王联系了联合国
The King of Atlantis has reached out to the United Nations
正式请求成为会员国
and will be officially seeking membership.
并有望提出共同努力方案 来扭转气候问题
And is expected to propose a joint effort to reverse the climate issues.
据说这是与联合国在历经数周
We are told that this was the result of weeks of secret negotiations
-密谈后的结果 -本台将与艾力斯岛连线
- with the United Nations. - We now go live to Ellis Island,
直播亚特兰提斯的首位官方大使
where the first official ambassador from Atlantis
在联合国所发表的谈话
is about to address the United Nations.
今天我身为两个世界的代表来此
I come here today as a representative of two worlds.
陆地与海洋
The land and the sea.
我来到这里证明了两地都将迎来改变
And I stand here as proof that change is coming to both.
为应对全球危机我呼吁全球合作
And I'm calling for global unity for a global crisis.
好推进两地之间的和谐 以及我们世界的自然平衡
To finally bring harmony between us and the natural balance of our world.
亚特兰提斯随时准备提供协助 贡献我方的科学与技术
Atlantis stands ready to help contribute its science and technology.
凭藉你们对大气的了解 以及我们对海洋的了解
And with your knowledge of the air, and our knowledge of the seas,
我们可以一起写下彼此故事的下一章
together we can write the next chapter in our story,
而不是结局
rather than its ending.
有时我们的分歧会看似太过极端
Sometimes it's gonna seem like our differences are too extreme,
但我们只需要扪心自问
but all we have to do is look beneath the surface,
并了解到我们同在此星球上 更有着相同的目标和远景
to see that we're all here on this planet with the same goals and aspirations.
-即便两方的风俗 -给你
- Even when our customs... - Here you go.
-是如此迥异与陌生 -啤酒与起司汉堡
- ...might seem strange and unfamiliar. - Beer and a cheeseburger.
像你要求的那样额外多汁
Extra greasy like you asked for.
但透过克服我们的偏见
And by overcoming our prejudices,
我们会变得更加强大 并更为了解我们自己
we'll become stronger and learn more about ourselves.
我们可以抓住此契机 为了我们的孩子与家庭
We can seize this moment to create a better more hopeful future,
创造更美好并更有希望的未来
for our children, and our families.
我的名字是亚瑟库瑞
My name is Arthur Curry.
我是海底王国亚特兰提斯的法定君主
I'm the rightful sovereign of the undersea nation of Atlantis.
我是一位父亲、兄长
I'm a father, a brother,
战士 与友人
a warrior and a friend.
我是亚特兰提斯之王
I'm the King of Atlantis.
我是海王
I am Aquaman.
海王 失落王国
更多精彩影视 请访问荐片播放器 https://jianpian.app/